For many walk,
of whom I have told you often,
and now tell you even weeping,
that they are the enemies of the cross of Christ:
Philippians 3:18.
Two outwardly good deeds,
Two outwardly good lives,
yet completely inseparable to the human eye.
But one is right walk and the other is wrong walk.
The other is walking as an enemy of Christ's Cross
and the other is walking as a friend of Christ's Cross.
What kind of life do you walk?
It's great if you walk by doing good deeds,
cleanly, thru leading a restrained life
and by being in every way orderly and wholesome.
As Paul in the next verse writes,
for what reason it will ever happen
so even if that good life occurs as an enemy of Christ's Cross, it serves their stomach
— at least it gives them pay and enjoyment in that way.
But only for the duration of this life,
it is of no use to the future life.
We live in a country where in principle there should not be any lack of understanding of,
on how to walk as a Friend of Christ's Cross.
And yet, if you read this third chapter of Philippians —
it's too easy to arrive into a wrong understanding,
because of the lack of proper understanding,
that the topic would be about unrestrained life or something similar like that
which is not appropriate.
And yet the question is merely
what is the relationship between your own walk and Christ's cross.
The Cross of Christ separates the Christian from everybody else.
It matters why God became a man in Christ.
It matters why He reconciled all humanity on the cross.
It matters that — as a true God and a true man — He fulfilled all the obedience which God demands from man.
And that that very obedience is counted as the property and part of each and every Christian.
Without any merit, out of sheer grace,
for the sake of Jesus Christ.
I hope reaching someone who has walked a good life,
that's a valuable thing.
Maybe you have been baptized when you were very small.
In that you have been baptized into the death of Christ.
In that you have been baptized as a friend of the Cross of Christ.
Hold fast to it.
Do not let your good walk which you do out of a habit to be spilled only for duration of this life.
But walk among Christ's friends. With a good conscience.
Let's say that if you haven't attended a Divine Service for a long time,
if you haven't heard the gospel for a while,
if you haven't read your Bible recently.
You may be missing something essential from your daily bread.
For a man does not live by bread and food alone,
but by every word that proceeds out of the mouth of God.
So now that you already know — maybe not very actively, but nevertheless in some way —
that the most important treasure of this life is to know Christ aright.
Possessing the fact that God gladly regonizes you because of Christ's perfect obedience and perfect life.
For He has fulfilled every jot and every tittle from God's law.
In order for you to have that white garment in the last judgment before God, the perfect and pure life of Christ donated to you.
Because nothing less will be enough then.
So now rejoice.
Walk as a friend of the Cross of Christ.
Walk among the Lord's people.
Discover and find your own place where God's children gather together.
Hear the Word of God and notice how it feeds and strengthens you.
This difference between walking and walking,
it deepens the understanding of
that it really doesn't matter what a person reaches or how much time they have,
but in the end the only thing which matters really is that God forgives.
Remain in His good hands and in Christ's peace.
Scripture taken from the Holy Bible, King James Version.